低成本的个人电脑的出现使得一个强大的互联网有机会诞生，
of low-cost personal computers gave rise  to a powerful network that has
它为学习和交流提供了巨大的机会，
transformed opportunities for learning  and communicating the magical thing
网络的神奇之处，不仅仅是它缩短了物理距离，
about this network is not just that it  collapses distance，
使得天涯若比邻，
and makes everyone your neighbor.
它还极大地增加了具有共同想法的人们聚集在一起的机会，
it also dramatically increases the  number of brilliant minds we can bring
我们可以为了解决同一个问题一起共同工作，这就大大加快了革新的进程
into work together on the same problem.  and it skills up the rate of potential
发展速度简直快得让人震惊。与此同时，世界上有条件上网的人
innovation to a staggering degree. at the  same time for every person who has
只是全部人口的六分之一，这意味着，
access to this technology five people  don't，
还有许多具有创造性的人们没有加入到我们的讨论中来。
that means many creative minds are left  out of this discussion.
那些有着实际操作经验和相关经历的聪明人，却没有技术来帮助他们，
smart people with practical intelligence  and relevant experience who don't have
将他们的天赋或者想法与全世界分享。
the technology to hone their talents or  contribute their ideas to the world.
我们需要尽可能地让更多的人有机会使用新技术，
we need as many people as possible to  gain access to this technology because
因为这些新技术正在引发一场革命，
these advances are triggering a  revolution in human and what human
人类将因此可以互相帮助。
beings can do for one another.
新技术正在创造一种可能，不仅是政府，
they are making it possible not just for  national governments but for
还包括大学、公司、小机构甚至个人。
universities corporations small  or ganizations and even individuals to
能够发现问题所在，能够找到解决办法，能够评估他们努力的效果，
see problems see approaches and measure  the impact of their efforts to address
去改变那些马歇尔60年前 the hunger poverty and desperation
就提出过的问题---饥饿、贫穷和绝望。
George Marshall spoke up 60 years ago
哈佛是一个大家庭，这个院子在场的人们
members of the Harvard family here in  the yard is one of the great collections
是全世界最有智力的人类群体之一，
of intellectual talent in the world,
我们可以做些什么？毫无疑问，
for what purpose there is no question  that the faculty
哈佛的老师、校友、学生和资助者已经用他们的能力
the Alumni the students and the  benefactors of Harvard have used their
改善了全世界各地人们的生活，但是，我们还能够再做什么呢？
power to improve the lives of people  here and around the world but can we do
有没有可能，哈佛的人们可以将他们的智慧用来帮助那些甚至从来
more than Harvard dedicate its intellect  to improving the lives of people will
没有听到过“哈佛”这个名字的人。
never even hear its name
请允许我向各位院长和教授提出一个请求，你们是哈佛的
let me make a request of the deans and  the professor's the intellectual leaders
智力领袖，当你们雇佣新的老师，授予终身教职，评估课程
here at Harvard as you hire new faculty  award tenure review curriculum and
决定学位颁发标准的时候，请问你们自己如下的问题：
determine degree requirements please ask  yourself：should our best minds be more
我们最优先的人才是否在致力于解决我们最大的问题？
dedicated to solving our biggest problems should Harvard encourage its
哈佛是否鼓励她的老师去研究解决世界上最严重的不平等？
faculty to take on the world's worst in equity
哈佛的学生是否知道世界上那些极端的贫穷？
in harvard students know about the depth  of global poverty?
世界性的饥荒，清洁水资源的缺乏，
the prevalence of world hunger the  scarcity of clean water
无法上学的女童，死于本可治愈的疾病的儿童，
the girls get out of school the children  who die from diseases we can cure,
世界上过着最优越生活的人们，有没有了解到这个世界最贫穷的
should the world's most privileged learn  about the lives of the world's
人们的生活？
least privilege?
这些问题并非老生常谈。
these are not reported question
你必须用自己的行动来回答它们。
you will answer with your policies.
我母亲在我被哈佛大学录取的那一天，
My mother who is filled with pride
曾经感到非常骄傲，她从没有停止督促我去为他人做更多的事情。
the day i was admitted，her never stop  pressing me to do more for others.
在我结婚的前几天，她主持了一个新娘进我家的仪式，在这个仪式上，
A few days before I was married she hosted a bridal event and when she read aloud a
她高声朗读了一封关于婚姻的信，这是她写给Melinda的，那时，
letter about marriage that she had  written to Melinda my mother was very
我母亲已经因为癌症病入膏肓，但是她还是认为这是又一个
ill with cancer at the time but she saw  one more opportunity to deliver her
传播她的信念的机会，在那封信的结尾，她写道：你的能力越大，
message and at the close of the letter  she said from those to whom much is
人们对你的期望也就越高。
given much is expected.
想一想吧，我们在这个院子里的这些人，被给予过什么，
when you consider what those of us here  in this yard have been given in talent
天赋，特权，机遇，可以这样说，这个世界完全有权
privilege and opportunity there is  almost no limit to what the world has a
期待我们做出贡献，同这个时代的期望一样，
right to expect from us, in line with the  promise of this age,
我也要向今天各位毕业的同学提出一个忠告，
深刻的不平等的问题，然后你们要变成这个问题的专家，
a deep in equity and become a specialist on it.
如果你们能够使得这个问题成为你们职业的核心，那么你们就会非常杰出。
if you make it the focus of your career  that would be phenomenal.
但是你们不必一定要以此为职业，每个星期只用几个小时，
but you don't have to do that to make an  impact for a few hours every week
你就可以通过不断成长的互联网得到信息，
you can use the growing power of the  internet to get informed find others
找到志同道合的朋友，
with the same interests.
并发现困难所在，找到解决它们的途径，
see the barriers and find ways to cut  through them.
不要让世界的复杂性阻碍你前进，
don't let complexity stop you,
在解决人类的不平等事业中做一个积极的行动主义者。
be active activists take on big and  equities
它将成为你生命中最重要的经历之一，在座的各位毕业的同学
I feel sure it will be one of the great  experiences of your lives you graduates
你们所处的时代是一个神奇的时代，当你们离开哈佛的时候，你们拥有的
are coming of age in an amazing time as  you leave Harvard you have technology
技术是我们那一届学生所没有的，你们已经了解到了我们以前所不了解的
that members of my class never hand. You  have awareness of global equity which we
世界上的不平等。有了这样的了解之后，若再弃那些需要帮助的人们于不顾，
did not have, and with that awareness you  likely also have an informed conscience
必将受到良心的谴责。
that will torment you.
只需一点小小的努力，你就可以改变那些人们的生活。
if you abandon these people whose lives， you could change with modest effort you
你们拥有比我们更大的能力，
have more than we had,
你们必须尽早开始，尽可能长期坚持下去，我希望30年后，
you must start sooner and carry on  longer and I hope
你们还会再回到哈佛，回溯你们用自己的天赋和能力
you will come back here to Harvard 30  years from now and reflect on what
所做出的一切。我希望那时，
you've done with your talent and your energy
你们用来评价自己的标准，不仅仅是你们的专业成就，
I hope you will judge your selves not on  your professional accomplishments alone
还包括你们为改变这个世界深刻的不平等所做出的努力，
but also on how well you have addressed  the world's deepest inequities on how
以及你们如何善待那些远隔世界那边的人们，
well you treated people a world away
与你们毫不相关的人们，但他们也是人类！
we have nothing in common with you, but  their humanity!
祝各位好运！
good luck
长时间鼓掌......
Long applause......